hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast
my name is Jeremiah Krakowski and on
this podcast I help coaches mentors and
trainers make the most amount of money
possible in their business attract the
right clients and create
incredible lifestyle changes that will
make their dreams come true and that's
why I exist is to help coaches reach
their dreams financially
if you're a trainer if you're a mentor
if you're a thought leader if you're a
coach my goal is for you to become a
multi-millionaire
and by listening to this podcast it's my
way of helping you do that
this podcast deals with the most
important topics that are taken from my
highest level
coaching program and one-on-one coaching
calls with clients
where most podcasts might just deal with
surface level issues to attract their
customers we've taken a different
approach where we actually put our very
best content
into the podcast and so you can rely on
this podcast to provide you with Cutting
Edge strategies and information to help
you succeed in your business now today I
want to talk about something been
talking about it for a few of the
previous podcast episodes but it keeps
coming up it keeps coming up and and
the root of this topic that I want to
talk about is
that people
become so worried about making other
people happy
about pleasing other people about doing
what other people want them to do
and so then when they go out and try to
coach
they're worried about how other people
are going to react whether people are
going to be disappointed
whether people are going to be happy
with their information whether people
are going to like it
and this leads them to do something
that can almost guarantee that they
won't make any money in their coaching
business and I see it happen often and I
am passionate about this because
it's so prevalent
in the coaching industry
and the people who do it
are are so deeply interconnected with
this way of thinking
that they actually think that they're
serving their clients by doing it and
they are actually thinking that it's a
good thing what is this well
it's not making big enough and bold
enough promises
in your offers
in your particularly your free offers
particularly your free content
and
under
whelming your audience
because you don't want to push the
envelope and Promise Too Much
and a concern
and focus on over promising and under
delivering
and trying to under promise and over
deliver and thinking that that is an
actual strategy for success
it's not
it's not going to make you any money
and yet
and and I want to have just honor here
for everybody who's listening you may
believe
the complete opposite of what I've just
said
let me just ask you this have you have
you have you built multi-million dollar
coaching businesses in multiple niches
have you coached thousands of people on
how to build multi-million dollar
coaching businesses
successfully if the answer is no to that
then
you may want to pay attention to
somebody who has
when they have some advice for you
and this is one of the biggest areas
I'll tell you I've been telling people
this
for years I'll talk to the same person
and this one area they don't get and
it's the one area that if you can get it
it'll change your life financially
you know I did a I did a whole research
study
into this
I have listened to the presentations of
many very financially successful coaches
mentors and trainers out there
and
the ones who are most financially
successful
are not afraid to make incredible
promises
for even their free content
and here's why
your free content
needs to make the same bold promise that
your paid program has and it needs to do
so at such a level of boldness
that it is
100 percent impossible
for you to actually deliver
on that promise in the paid training
all right I'm going to say it again you
need to promise something that is so big
that you can't even
realistically deliver it
in the free training
and that's where I lose people most of
the time
and there's any number of reasons why
people are unable to do this and I can
address those and and I was just having
a conversation with a coaching client
today all about this all about
where this comes from
I'm actually going through some of my
notes Here
just to take a look at this
what I often hear from coaches is that
they don't want
to
disappoint people
with their free offer
and
they want to make sure that since
obviously like they can't deliver the
whole big thing
all at once in the free training that
they don't promise it as well
because they want to only talk about
exactly what's going to actually be
talked about in the free training
exactly what's actually going to be
talked about the problem is we've tested
this over and over and over again
and while that sounds great in theory
that's a recipe to never make a dime in
your coaching business
and so what you have to do is you have
to flip your perspective and you can
handle this two different ways
is you make a bold promise something
that you will never be able to
accomplish
in your free offer in your webinar in
your challenge it's so big that
generally the person is going to
probably need about six to 12 months of
working with you to even actually
experience that final result that final
outcome
now here's why you can do so with
integrity
here's why
see if if you actually follow me and
actually understand where I'm coming
from you'll you'll know
that I that only what I teach comes from
a place of honesty and integrity and
that's what I'm gonna lead you with
what you do is on your landing page with
the offer
you're going to make that really bold
promise
something that might take them 12 months
24 months five years 10 years even to
reach that goal and here's why you can
do so with Integrity even if it is a
thousand and one percent impossible for
you to actually deliver that result in
your free content I think it's hilarious
that just if I look at the stats on this
podcast how many people
log off and won't listen and aren't
listening at this point of the podcast
because they prejudge what I'm actually
saying what I'm meaning so if you're
still here if you're still listening to
me
thank you thank you for actually
trusting me to go on this journey with
you here's why you can do so with
integrity
because
your free content right here
is Step number one
on
that promised Journey
and that that you're basically giving
them a demo
a free trial
at this point
step number one
that's it
and so you are actually being honest
about the fact that when they join your
free training
that the promised result will come to
pass for them if they continue on the
journey with you
now a lot of people ask you know how do
you know how much to give away how much
content to give away
and then when to you know
tell people that they need to buy the
next level
and this is where people's thinking is
wrong see they think it's about holding
back a certain amount of content so that
you have enough to charge people for and
that's a complete misdirection of of
focus
see when we when we when we don't
disconnect
step one and maybe even step two and
three for me I give away pretty much
steps one two three four and five in my
free content and then you go from like
six to twenty in my paid content I give
you a lot for free in a lot of my free
content a lot of free value
over delivering absolutely
but it's because it's strategically
designed because I know that there's so
much more right here and I'm not holding
anything back over here see that's the
key is you don't want to hold back
anything over here however
don't make the mistake of Simply
blasting people with information
in order to try to validate yourself and
prove to yourself to people
that they should work with you simply
because you gave them a lot of
information nobody's gonna buy from you
simply because you gave them a lot of
great information
so you have to actually craft a sales
pitch in a way that makes a connection
with somebody and so what you want to do
in your free offer
is this is you demonstrating what it's
like to work with you
and you're making that initial that
initial connection with them over here
the amount of content and information
that you actually share may not even
scratch the surface of what you actually
pay for and charge but what you're going
to do is you're going to invite people
into your ecosystem when we talk about
an ecosystem it's your world it's your
environment it's the growth place of the
results that you create for people when
people join with me they are entering an
environment where they will grow if they
take action on what I teach
now I teach a lot of stuff that
challenges many of the ways that we have
been trained raised best practices of
society and what people believe is even
right and proper to do
and this is why most people will not do
the things it takes to be successful if
you start simply after this episode
applying what I'm sharing right now
you'll be ahead of 98 of coaches and
mentors out there and yet
most people will refuse to do what I'm
talking about in favor of the latest fad
Guru strategy
cracks me up
when what I'm talking about right now is
actually what produces the greatest
result for you now here's what's cool is
when you create a bold promise in your
offer during this time of connection
here see this is why I'm I'm excited
like I'm thankful for those of you that
are still listening to me right now
you know
people start podcast episodes and then
stop them all the time for those that
are still listening
it's gonna be a huge unlock for you
during your presentation
you can be transparent and say Hey
listen
I want to start you on a journey
I'm going to show you how to experience
XYZ result the gal I was working with
today she teaches people how to play
music by ear it's going to take more
than just an hour and a half webinar to
do that and so what I said is she needs
to say
frankly
it's impossible for me to teach you
everything there is to know in an hour
and a half but what I'm going to do is
I'm going to pack as much information
that I know will be valuable to you
right now to start this journey because
I know that if you start with me on this
you will be able to reach those goals
that you have and I can help you get
there that's transparent that's honest
so you make the Bold Promise by inviting
people into your ecosystem and then you
transparently explain
the reality of what's going on during
your presentation I'll tell you if you
do that I get I'll tell you what will
happen nobody's going to complain about
it in fact they're going to thank you
and they're going to say it was the best
presentation they ever had
now listen you may get some people that
are disappointed some people that are
going to complain
there's always going to be those
negative people that are looking for a
fight looking to challenge the man
looking to to to X
expose people quote unquote
and you're just gonna have to stop
worrying about what they think about you
I got people all the time that tell me
that what I teach is wrong and terrible
and even what I'm telling you right now
there are people
who would be livid
to even know what I'm sharing what's
funny is I put it out there in the
public I don't hide it it's not even
behind a paywall
like literally publicly available
I'm probably one of the few coaches that
actually tells you the truth about this
up front
you don't gotta pay me twenty Thirty
forty thousand dollars to get the truth
on this
because I want to see you succeed
and I want to see you make
the kind of money that I know is
possible in this type of business
but if you're not willing
to make bold promises
and you're not willing
to disappoint a few people
you get 100 people who sign up two
people are pissed off because you didn't
touch on what they wanted you to touch
on and you actually touched on what
connected with the other 98 of people
when
yeah you'll get
whiners complainers whatever you will
but don't shift your entire business
model just to appease and please the one
or two people that get disappointed
that's craziness
and yet that is what most coaches do
because there is
generally can be deal with unresolved
trauma your family of origin how you
grew up
you're in or your environment right now
or the environment that you came out of
whether it be a workplace a job a church
or a situation where usually
some kind of maybe an authority figure
or somebody who put themselves in
Authority was very critical of you
and very harsh and made it in some way
unsafe for you
to disappoint them and by the way safety
is relative doesn't necessarily mean
physical unsafety but it could be as
simple as you would lose your job or
something like that if you disappointed
them and so then we bring that into a
coaching interaction we bring that into
our coaching business
the timidity the fear
of upsetting others
stops us from doing the very things that
will make us the most amount of money in
our business
and so what I encourage people to do is
take whatever your business model is and
go into chat GPT and we have prompts
that you can use for this you can ask it
what is the ultimate dream outcome that
somebody who goes through this type of
coaching might experience and then you
you start to promise that to people
your offer should not be connected to
what your coaching methodology is or
we're gonna do some testing on you and
you're gonna get
all the labs you need to figure out
what's wrong with you and your health
nobody's gonna buy that no what they
want to buy is that you're going to have
more energy than you had when you were
15 years old
even if you're in your 40s
and that you're going to be able to
accomplish more than you ever thought
was possible for you at your age
that's a bold promise
and far too often people are leading
with what
they're selling what their coaching is
what their methodology is instead of the
Ultimate Dream outcome and selling the
dream
selling the dream that by the way
most people are probably never actually
going to experience because of their
inability to change their behavior and
that's what most of the reasons why
people never succeed are is their
inability to change their behavior
and it's not a flaw of yours as a coach
by the way
see I've taken radical personal
responsibility over
how can I contribute how have I
contributed to people's failure
um
in my coaching business and when I look
at okay well at at some point
if they're not listening to the training
they're not responding to any kind of
reach out or accountability they're
ignoring everything
about the program
aside from me showing up their front
door which would be kind of creepy I
have literally done everything in my
power to help this person succeed and
they've explicitly chosen to not change
their behavior
and to not get the most out of their
investment in the coaching that they
paid for
and you'll find that in your business
this is most of your clients this is
most of the people that are actually
going to sign up for your training and
your coaching you got to be okay with
that
and you'll even have a small percentage
that are going to be disappointed by
this
and generally most of the time they're
going to complain it's usually always
always
if you are delivering enough content
which is what we do the number one thing
that people come to me and complain
about is that I'm not giving them enough
one-on-one support which by the way I
don't give one-on-one support and I
charge for the one-on-one support and so
the ultimate complaint is that my
one-on-one coaching is too expensive and
because I'm so greedy that's why they
could never succeed
and I'm just like you know sorry uh I'm
not gonna devalue my pricing simply
because you feel that way and because
you lack the self-discipline to be able
to listen to a training you lack the
self-discipline to be able to go through
the content and you are unable to even
show up to ask questions because of your
own embarrassment and I get it some of
that might be mental health issues they
need therapy they need some help
I recommend tons of resources to help
people but at the end of the day if
they're not willing to show up in their
business
and actually do the work
they've chosen the results that they've
gotten
and their actions show it you know I got
a guy he he joins everything that I do
you might leave and listen to this
podcast I don't care
never takes action but he joins
everything that I do and his number one
reason is I just don't I just you know I
just uh I just don't feel comfortable
doing it I don't feel ready yet well
yeah he hasn't felt ready yet for like
eight years no but
he won't even apply any of the advice
that he's given
but I guess he's getting some value out
of it he keeps showing up you know there
are actually coaches out there that
believe that I should prevent him from
buying from me
and then it's unethical
to allow him to purchase my coaching
from me
I think that's silly
especially if it's a group coaching
program
if you make an opportunity for people
and they decide to purchase it and you
make it very clear about the
expectations
and by the way again we gotta stop over
promising
or under promising over delivering we
gotta stop over over over giving so much
of ourselves to people I know people
that they would literally give hours and
hours and hours of their time for free
to codependent and toxically help their
clients
reach their goals
because they find a sense of self-worth
in people using them
and when you detach your self-worth and
your self-esteem from people's ability
to use you
and by the way
you know this is the same root cause of
why
people
um
are promiscuous and they do things that
they regret and maybe they sleep with
people that they don't want to uh just
to feel validation Again by the way you
know
and I know what it's like I used to be
like this I used to be somebody who
felt I had no self-worth and my
validation came from people telling me
how how awesome I was
it people using me and people using my
coaching at this point now I'm like
I'm gonna provide the information I'm
going to give you the best information
out there but it's on you to actually
take action with it because I know that
I've set up all the systems that I can
in my power in the best ability that I
have at the highest level possible
and so at the end of the day
the responsibility then falls back on
the client to be able to actually
utilize and take action in what is
promised and so that's why I confidently
and boldly will make promises to people
about what they can accomplish when they
enter our ecosystem
unashamed
and we've gotten to the point now where
we we've targeted the right customer
I have my my sales pitch dialed down
where I actually get very few complaints
anymore from people too
which is actually that's a really
beautiful thing when you learn how to
communicate well when you learn how to
powerfully
lead the room quote unquote in your
presentation
and you're able to be transparent and
even address and handle objections with
confidence
you'll let people thanking you even if
you held back quote unquote information
that would help them and ultimately you
know some people actually need you to
hold back information if you overload
people with information in your
challenges or in your webinars you're
not actually helping anybody
you're only serving the internal
need
for feeling like well I did all the
things I did all the right stuff I gave
them all the information
at the end of the day the most important
thing that you can do is make a
connection emotionally with the prospect
to help them see the possibility
of where they're going and we have a
whole methodology of how we craft our
webinars what you say during them how do
you say things how do you actually get
people to buy from you
and the majority of it is in framing
their Vision framing their mindset
framing what they can see as a
possibility injecting possibilities that
they never thought were possible into
their mind
and what's funny is when you can mirror
with the right people and essentially
read their mind as to what they want and
you say the things that they actually
want and how can we do this we can
predict with accuracy by writing the
right sales copy and using artificial
intelligence to Target the right people
on social media
we're able to do this
and we're able to find the right people
that were meant to work with that were
meant to connect with
very easily
and then close sales by communicating
with that group of people okay
and so if you're a coach if you're a
trainer if you're a mentor and you want
to know
oh do I build a coaching business
successfully I would encourage you if
you're not part of my client growth
accelerator program get on the waiting
list to jump into the client growth
accelerator group coaching program it's
the best program that's out there for
coaches for mentors four trainers to be
able to get the information the support
the accountability
everything that you need to be to make
sure that you never get stuck in
building your coaching business you have
at your disposal as part of my coaching
program and if you're listening to this
podcast you also have access to me on my
social media you can ask me questions
anytime you want you can go post on my
social media the one thing I don't do is
I don't respond to direct messages
but you can comment back to me on any
social media platform and I'll comment
I'll comment back
it's funny I say that a lot and most
people still never take me up on it not
sure why but it's their own choice
so
listen I believe that you can succeed
and make a million dollars as a coach
I believe that you can reach those goals
but you have to stop
tiptoeing the line and being afraid to
speak into existence a bold future
outcome for your Target customer you
need to prophesy into their life what is
possible
that's what it is you need to directly
speak the possibilities that your target
client can have and if you struggle to
see the possibilities in your own life
that's one of the best places to start
is to actually work on what's going on
between your own head and to actually
take care of what's going on in your own
heart
and then that will make you Unstoppable
when it comes to helping your clients I
believe in you and I love seeing you
succeed thanks for listening to this
episode
we'll talk soon have a good one
[Music]
[Applause]